# Adigun Itabiyi

# Registered Pharmacist - AVENUE PHARMACY

Brookhaven, PA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Adigun-Itabiyi/c0c4593aa5ba000d

Licensed pharmacist in Pennsylvania with MS Pharmacy degree and over twenty years of experience providing top-notch pharmacy services in hospital and retail setting. Passionate and motivated, with a drive for excellence. Outstanding interpersonal skills with a track record of establishing positive relationships with customers, medical professionals, healthcare organizations and insurance providers. Motivated leader with strong organizational and prioritization abilities. Handles tasks with accuracy and efficiency.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## **Registered Pharmacist**

AVENUE PHARMACY - Chester, PA - 2016 to Present

Responsibilities include, but not limited to:

Service and satisfy customer health needs Prepare and fill new and refill orders

Openly communicate with customers while protecting their confidential health and drug information

Provide counseling to patients having medical questions

Solicit information on patients' medical history to give appropriate medical advice Appropriate inventory management.

Review prescriptions to assure accuracy, to ascertain the needed ingredients, and to evaluate their suitability.

Provide information and advice regarding drug interactions, side effects, dosage, and proper medication storage.

Assess the identity, strength, or purity of medications.

Compound and dispense medications as prescribed by doctors and dentists, by calculating, weighing, measuring, and mixing ingredients, or oversee these activities.

Maintain records, such as pharmacy files, patient profiles, charge system files, inventories, control records for radioactive nuclei, or registries of poisons, narcotics, or controlled drugs.

Plan, implement, or maintain procedures for mixing, packaging, or labeling pharmaceuticals, according to policy and legal requirements, to ensure quality, security, and proper disposal.

Advise customers on the selection of medication brands, medical equipment, or healthcare supplies.

Offer health promotion and prevention activities, for example, training people to use devices such as blood pressure or diabetes monitors.

#### Pharmacy Intern

AVENUE PHARMACY - Chester, PA - July 2014 to May 2015

Review prescriptions to assure accuracy, to ascertain the needed ingredients, and to evaluate their suitability.

Provide information and advice regarding drug interactions, side effects, dosage, and proper medication storage.

Assess the identity, strength, or purity of medications.

Maintain records, such as pharmacy files, patient profiles, charge system files, inventories, control records for radioactive nuclei, or registries of poisons, narcotics, or controlled drugs.

Compound and dispense medications as prescribed by doctors and dentists, by calculating,

weighing, measuring, and mixing ingredients, or oversee these activities.

Offer health promotion and prevention activities, for example, training people to use devices such as blood pressure or diabetes monitors.

#### Pharmacy technician

DUANE READE PHARMACY - Manhattan, NY - October 2013 to January 2014

**Daily Medication Smart Count** 

Pre-pack bulk medicines, fill bottles with prescribed medications, and type and affix labels.

Maintain proper storage and security conditions for drugs.

Answer telephones, responding to questions or requests.

Mix pharmaceutical preparations, according to written prescriptions.

Prepare and process medical insurance claim forms and records.

Assist customers by answering simple questions, locating items, or referring them to the pharmacist for medication information.

Receive and store incoming supplies, verify quantities against invoices, check for outdated medications in current inventory, and inform supervisors of stock needs and shortages.

Operate cash registers to accept payment from customers.

## Pharmacist-in-Charge

68 NIGERIAN ARMY REFERENCE HOSPITAL YABA - Lagos - April 2001 to April 2013

Lagos

Review prescriptions to assure accuracy, to ascertain the needed ingredients, and to evaluate their suitability.

Provide information and advice regarding drug interactions, side effects, dosage, and proper medication storage.

Assess the identity, strength, or purity of medications.

Maintain records, such as pharmacy files, patient profiles, charge system files, inventories, control records for radioactive nuclei, or registries of poisons, narcotics, or controlled drugs.

Compound and dispense medications as prescribed by doctors and dentists, by calculating, weighing, measuring, and mixing ingredients, or oversee these activities.

Plan, implement, or maintain procedures for mixing, packaging, or labeling pharmaceuticals, according to policy and legal requirements, to ensure quality, security, and proper disposal.

Teach pharmacy students serving as interns in preparation for their graduation or licensure.

Provide specialized services to help patients manage conditions such as diabetes, asthma, smoking cessation, or high blood pressure.

Collaborate with other health care professionals to plan, monitor, review, or evaluate the quality or effectiveness of drugs or drug regimens, providing advice on drug applications or characteristics.

Analyze prescribing trends to monitor patient compliance and to prevent excessive usage or harmful interactions.

Order and purchase pharmaceutical supplies, medical supplies, or drugs, maintaining stock and storing and handling it properly

Offer health promotion and prevention activities, for example, training people to use devices such as blood pressure or diabetes monitors.

Publish educational information for other pharmacists, doctors, or patients.

### **EDUCATION**

# **Master of Pharmacy in Pharmacy**

UNIVERSITY OF LAGOS Nigeria January 2004

# **Bachelor of Science in Pharmacy**

AHMADU BELLO UNIVERSITY August 1985

### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

### Skills

- Endurance to work long hours, often standing up Ability to work as part of a healthcare team and a positive attitude
- Ability to handle multiple tasks and heavy Ability to work one-on-one with patients workloads Organizational skills, to be responsible for
- A desire to help people and improve the quality systems which control drug distribution of their lives Enjoy working with a geriatric community
- A strong ability to communicate clearly and effectively and interact well with people